<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Based Cooking</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/</link>
<description>blog</description>
<item>
<title>Garam Masala</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/garam-masala.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/garam-masala.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 04:31:43 +0200</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Garam Masala</h1>

<p>A spice mixture for most Indian dishes</p>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>4 Green Cardamom</li>
<li>2 Black Cardamom</li>
<li>1 tbsp Coriander</li>
<li>2 Cloves</li>
<li>1 tbsp Cumin</li>
<li>1 tbsp Fennel seeds</li>
<li>5/6 Bayleaf</li>
<li>5/6 Black pepper pods</li>
<li>1 Star anise (Optional)</li>
<li>Mace (Optional): Mace is a dried flower originating from the Nutmeg plant. Use no more than 3 strands of this flower.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Star anise and Mace are normally not added to Garam masala. They are added specially if someone is making <a href="lamb-biriyani.html">Biriyani</a>.</li>
<li>Cloves will make the masala really hot. So make sure to add only as much as you want to eat.</li>
<li>Too much Mace makes the masala quite bitter. So make sure you do not add more than what has been recommended. The amount of other spices can be changed according to taste.</li>
<li>Wash all the dry spices really well.</li>
<li>If you live in a place which is very sunny, sun dry your washed spices for about 1 day. If not then on a frying pan with a heavy bottom, place all the spices and dry roast them until aromatic.</li>
<li>Cool the dry spices and put them into a mixer. Mix thoroughly.</li>
<li>Sieve the powder and add the larger pieces into the mixer once again and mix it again until everything turns into a fine powder. This step might need to be repeated a few times.</li>
<li>The resulting mixture is garam masala. Store it in airtight glass jars.</li>
<li>You can store this mixture for about 2/3 months in a cool dry place.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Chetan Basuray

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/chetanbasuray">website</a></li>
<li>btc: <code>199H7ee5t3D2N1fnpUmFEqfVMqe3aq4eMr</code></li>
<li>eth: <code>0x911f88ac1e699f111a22a1b4049e44ef8e8b08cb</code></li>
<li>monero: <code>84PTQNJeyUuTVHN3daWwmPLBCL5GLt4WB14e2ZqFMu5kiPZDgst5hVUPVjVmdJJCvpPdi3Tt6KU853JxSQY3xCHPUtLECbt</code></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: indian spice</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ukrainian Borscht</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/ukrainian-borscht.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/ukrainian-borscht.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 02:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Ukrainian Borscht</h1>

<p>Borsch is a beet soup that originates from Ukraine and is common in Eastern Europe and North Asia.
Depending on the recipe, borscht may be purely vegetarian; it may be served either hot or cold; and it may range from a hearty one-pot meal to a clear broth or a smooth drink.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 25 mins</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 40 mins</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 10</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>3 red beetroots</li>
<li>4 Tbsp extra virgin olive oil</li>
<li>8 cups chicken broth + 2 cups water</li>
<li>3 yukon potatoes</li>
<li>2 carrots</li>
<li>2 celery ribs</li>
<li>1 onion</li>
<li>4 Tbsp ketchup or 3 Tbsp tomato sauce</li>
<li>1 red bell pepper (optional)</li>
<li>1 can white cannelini beans with their juice (optional)</li>
<li>2 bay leaves (optional)</li>
<li>1 pressed garlic clove (optional)</li>
<li>1 cup sour cream (optional)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Peel, grate and/or slice all vegetables (keeping sliced potatoes in cold water to prevent browning until ready to use then drain).</li>
<li>Heat a large soup pot (5 &frac12; Qt or larger) over medium/high heat and add 2 Tbsp olive oil.</li>
<li>Add grated beets and sauté 10 minutes, stirring occasionally until beets are softened.</li>
<li>Add 8 cups broth and 2 cups water.</li>
<li>Add sliced potatoes and sliced carrots then cook for 10-15 minutes or until easily pierced with a fork.</li>
<li>While potatoes are cooking, place a large skillet over medium/high heat and add 2 Tbsp oil.</li>
<li>Add chopped onion, celery and bell pepper. Saute stirring occasionally until softened and lightly golden (7-8 minutes).</li>
<li>Add 4 Tbsp Ketchup and stir fry for 30 seconds then transfer to the soup pot to continue cooking with the potatoes.</li>
<li>When potatoes and carrots reach desired softness, add optional ingredients from the list.</li>
<li>Simmer for an additional 2-3 minutes and add more spices to taste.</li>
<li>Serve with a dollop of sour cream on top.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contributors</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Stanislav</strong> – <a href="http://git.io/monesonn">link</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: ukrainian soup beetroot</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Coriander Chicken</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/coriander-chicken.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/coriander-chicken.html</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 17:15:48 +0200</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Coriander Chicken</h1>

<p>Boneless chicken marinated in a gravy of yoghurt and coriander</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 20 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 3</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>500g boneless chicken breast</li>
<li>250g fat free yoghurt</li>
<li>250g coriander leaves</li>
<li>Mustard oil / Sunflower oil</li>
<li>Sugar</li>
<li>Ginger</li>
<li>Garlic</li>
<li>2 medium onions</li>
<li>Green chillies</li>
<li><a href="garam-masala.html">Garam masala</a></li>
<li>2/3 Cardamom pods</li>
<li>1 Bayleaf</li>
<li>1 Cinnamom stick</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Cut the boneless chicken into small bite sized pieces.</li>
<li>In a mixer, put 250g coriander leaves, 2/3 green chillies, 250g yoghurt, 20g ginger, 9/10 cloves of garlic, 2 medium sized onions and mix well.</li>
<li>Add the green chillies according to your taste.</li>
<li>Pour half of the mixture from step 2 into a bowl and mix it thoroughly with the chicken.</li>
<li>Into this chicken mixture add 1 tbsp Garam Masala and salt to taste.</li>
<li>Keep the resulting marinated chicken aside for about 30 minutes.</li>
<li>In a frying pan add 3 tbsp of either mustard oil or sunflower oil.</li>
<li>Once the oil is hot, add 1 tbsp sugar and cook until the sugar melts into the oil.</li>
<li>Add 2/3 cardamom pods, 1 small cinnamon stick, and 1 bayleaf into the hot oil.</li>
<li>Simmer for about 1 minute, then lower the heat to medium.</li>
<li>On medium heat, add the marinated chicken mixture and cook till oil starts separating from the chicken.</li>
<li>Add salt to taste and keep stirring the chicken to make sure it does not burn or stick to the bottom of the pan.</li>
<li>Once the oil separates, add the remaining mixture which was left behind after step 4.</li>
<li>Stir until it has a thick consistency. Serve with <a href="naan-bread.html">naan</a> or <a href="rice.html">rice</a>.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Chetan Basuray

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/chetanbasuray">website</a></li>
<li>btc: <code>199H7ee5t3D2N1fnpUmFEqfVMqe3aq4eMr</code></li>
<li>eth: <code>0x911f88ac1e699f111a22a1b4049e44ef8e8b08cb</code></li>
<li>monero: <code>84PTQNJeyUuTVHN3daWwmPLBCL5GLt4WB14e2ZqFMu5kiPZDgst5hVUPVjVmdJJCvpPdi3Tt6KU853JxSQY3xCHPUtLECbt</code></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: indian lunch spicy</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hoisin Pork Belly</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/hoisin-pork-belly.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/hoisin-pork-belly.html</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 11:35:34 -0400</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Hoisin Pork Belly</h1>

<p><img src="pix/hoisin-pork-belly.webp" alt="Spicy Glazed Hoisin Pork Belly" /></p>

<p>Melt-in-mouth fatty pork in a sweet and spicy glaze.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 1 hr 15 mins</li>
<li>🍽  Servings: 2</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>400g high fat pork belly (no skin)</li>
<li>large thumb of ginger</li>
<li>4 cloves of garlic</li>
<li>1 scotch bonnet chili</li>
<li>2 tbsp ketchup</li>
<li>2 tbsp hoisin sauce</li>
<li>2 tbsp honey</li>
<li>2 tsp sesame oil</li>
<li>1 spring onion</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Cut pork belly into 1 inch cubes.</li>
<li>In a small frying pan place pork cubes fattiest side down in dry pan, put gas on lowest level possible flame, cover with lid. Ideally your pork covers the entire surface of the small pan&mdash;crowding is good for this recipe.</li>
<li>Lard will render out of the pork allowing it to confit cook in its own juice. Low flame essential. Turn the pork 3 or 4 times until all sides are golden and fat is rendered to melt in mouth levels. This will take around 1hr.</li>
<li>Remove pork belly and place in a bowl and cover. Remove around half the liquified lard and store for other uses.</li>
<li>Add diced ginger, smashed garlic cloves and chopped chili and sauté in the remaining lard. Once these are softened add the ketchup, hoisin sauce and honey. Reduce over very low heat for a few minutes until thickened.</li>
<li>Add the pork belly to the sauce and cook on low for a further 2 minutes. Leave to stand for 5 minutes then add thinly sliced spring onions to garnish. Enjoy with steamed white rice.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<p>speaker scorned</p>

<p>;tags: chinese pork spicy sweet</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Torrijas</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/torrijas.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/torrijas.html</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:24:43 +0200</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Torrijas</h1>

<p><img src="pix/torrijas.webp" alt="Torrijas" /></p>

<p>Torrijas are a spanish dessert traditionally eaten during the Holy Week (Easter).
It is said they were first cooked using the leftovers from the Lent.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 1 min</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 5 min</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>Dried bread (or Torrijas bread). Must be bread from a regular loaf, not from a tin loaf.</li>
<li>Milk (to soak the bread, 2 cups per 16 torrijas approx.)</li>
<li>Eggs (to coat the bread, 2 eggs per 16 torrijas approx.)</li>
<li>Cinnamon</li>
<li>Grated lemon rind (optional)</li>
<li>Sugar</li>
<li>Olive oil</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Mull the milk with cinnamon and a bit of sugar (not too much, the milk is already sweet). Add the lemon rind if you want.</li>
<li>Cool down the milk.</li>
<li>While the milk is cooling, beat the eggs and heat up half a pan of olive oil.</li>
<li>Cut the dry bread in slices. Soak it in the milk.</li>
<li>Coat the bread soaking it in the beaten eggs.</li>
<li>Fry the soaked &amp; coated bread with the heated oil.</li>
<li>Optionally sprinkle some sugar onto the Torrijas.</li>
<li>Enjoy when they are cooled down. Don&rsquo;t eat too much, it won&rsquo;t be easy resisting!</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>danoloan</strong> - <a href="https://danoloan.es">webpage</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: spanish dessert quick traditional easter</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Shepherd's Pie</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/shepherds-pie.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/shepherds-pie.html</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:23:05 +0200</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Shepherd&rsquo;s Pie</h1>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 50 - 60 min</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 30 - 40 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 8</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>600 grams (g) of mealy/floury potatoes</li>
<li>2 onions</li>
<li>2 carrots</li>
<li>4 tablespoons (tbsp.) of oil</li>
<li>800 g of minced lamb</li>
<li>100 g of frozen peas</li>
<li>2 tbsp. of tomato paste/puree</li>
<li>300 milliliters (ml) beef stock</li>
<li>1 tbsp. of sweet or smoked paprika</li>
<li>30 g of butter</li>
<li>200 ml of milk</li>
<li>1 pinch of nutmeg</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Peel potatoes, cut into cubes and boil in saltwater for 20 minutes. Peel the onions and carrots and cut into small cubes.</li>
<li>Heat the oil in a pan and fry the minced meat until crumbly. Add the onions, carrots and peas. Add the tomato paste and beef stock. Stir well and season with paprika, pepper and salt.</li>
<li>Drain potatoes and mash with butter. Add milk, season with nutmeg and stir until creamy.</li>
<li>Preheat the oven to 200°C. Grease a casserole dish with butter, put the minced meat in it and spread the mashed potatoes on it with a piping bag. Put the dish in the oven for 30-40 minutes.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<p><strong>Lázaro Blanc</strong> - <a href="https://blnc.io">Website</a> | <a href="https://github.com/lazaroblanc">GitHub</a> | <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lazaroblanc">LinkedIn</a> | <a href="https://www.xing.com/profile/Lazaro_Blanc">Xing</a></p>

<p>;tags: english lamb pie</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lebanese Lentil Soup</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/lebanese-lentil-soup.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/lebanese-lentil-soup.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 18:22:17 -0400</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Lebanese Lentil Soup</h1>

<p>Lebanese-Style Lentil Soup with Swiss Chard and Lemon</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 30 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 8</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>3 cups red lentils</li>
<li>12 cups water</li>
<li>1 large red onion, diced</li>
<li>2 small Yukon gold potatoes, diced</li>
<li>1 medium zucchini, diced</li>
<li>4 cups Swiss chard, chopped</li>
<li>1 bunch of cilantro, chopped</li>
<li>¼ cup of lemon juice, more to taste</li>
<li>1 teaspoon cumin</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>In a large pot, add lentils and water and place on medium heat to boil.</li>
<li>In a pan, sauté onions until pink, about 5 minutes. Add chopped Swiss chard and sauté together until chard is wilted, 2-3 minutes.</li>
<li>After lentils have cooked about 8 minutes, add onion chard mixture, along with diced potatoes and zucchini to the boiling water.</li>
<li>Add salt and pepper to taste.</li>
<li>Reduce heat to medium-low, cover the pot, and cook until the potatoes and lentils are completely cooked, about 12 minutes.</li>
<li>Add the chopped cilantro. Stir and cook for about 5 minutes.</li>
<li>Add lemon juice and cumin before serving.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Skipper Davies <a href="https://github.com/ferociousmadman">github</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: soup mediterranean lebanese</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Smoked Turkey</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/turkey-smoked.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/turkey-smoked.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 17:25:12 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Smoked Turkey</h1>

<p>Turkey, smoked on a charcoal grill</p>

<p><img src="pix/turkey-smoked-1.webp" alt="Smoked Turkey" /></p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 120 min</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 90-180 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 4 4-15</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>1 turkey, 5-15 lb. (thawed)</li>
<li>1-2 cups whipped butter (room temperature)</li>
<li>2 cup chicken broth</li>
<li>1-4 tbsp garlic powder (optional)</li>
<li>1 lb mixed vegetables (carrots, potatoes, broccoli, etc.) (optional)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Mix garlic powder into the whipped butter.</li>
<li>Remove giblets and other materials from the turkey cavity.</li>
<li>Rinse the turkey and pat dry with a towel.</li>
<li>Liberally coat the turkey with the whipped butter mixture. Ensure the entire surface is coated.</li>
<li>Place turkey in a foil baking pan with mixed vegatbles. If available, use a rack to elevate the turkey from the bottom of the pan.</li>
<li>Add chicken broth until it coats the bottom of the pan.</li>
<li>Cover the pan in foil.</li>
<li>Ignite the charcoal grill; arrange the coals for indirect cooking. Try to maintain a temperature of 300-400°F.</li>
<li>Place the turkey in pan on the grill and cook indirectly for 1 hour.</li>
<li>Remove the foil, and continue cooking over indirect heat.</li>
<li>Periodically (every 15-30 minutes) baste the turkey with its own juices. If the bottom of the pan is dry, add chicken broth and reduce heat.</li>
<li>Remove when the turkey reaches an internal temperature of 160°F in the breast.</li>
<li>Allow to rest for 10 minutes before carving.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Daddy Warcrimes - <a href="https://daddywarcrimes.blogspot.com/">website</a>, <a href="https://daddywarcrimes.blogspot.com/2018/05/why-im-asking-for-money.html">donate</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: basic american turkey</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cole Slaw</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/cole-slaw.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/cole-slaw.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 17:24:23 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Cole Slaw</h1>

<p>This is a cole slaw recipe that I got from a chili restaurant in my neighborhood that closed down a few years ago. This recipe makes more dressing than needed for the slaw, so you can save it or use it as a vegetable dip.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 25 min</li>
<li>🥶 Fridge time: 1 hr</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 8 - 10</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>&frac34; cup mayonnaise</li>
<li>&frac12; cup buttermilk</li>
<li>3 tbsp lemon juice</li>
<li>3 tbsp apple cider vinegar</li>
<li>4 tbsp distilled vinegar</li>
<li>1/3 cup canola oil</li>
<li>&frac14; cup granulated sugar</li>
<li>1 &frac12; tsp kosher salt</li>
<li>1 tsp ground black pepper</li>
<li>1 tsp celery seeds</li>
<li>&frac12; tsp onion powder</li>
<li>&frac14; tsp granulated garlic</li>
<li>&frac14; tsp mustard powder</li>
<li>One large head of green cabbage</li>
<li>One large carrot</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Finely shred, rinse, and drain the carrot</li>
<li>Finely shred the cabbage (use a food processor if possible)</li>
<li>Whisk together the mayonnaise, buttermilk, lemon juice, cider vinegar, distilled vinegar, canola oil, and sugar</li>
<li>Add the salt, pepper, celery seeds, onion powder, and granulated garlic, and combine well</li>
<li>Combine the shredded cabbage and carrot in a separate bowl</li>
<li>Slowly add the dressing until it lightly coats the vegetables, and toss well. Add more dressing until it tastes good</li>
<li>Refrigerate for at least an hour before serving</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Declan Cash - <a href="https://declancash.com">website</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: side cabbage southern salad</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spicy Mayo</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/spicy-mayo.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/spicy-mayo.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 16:22:47 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Spicy Mayo</h1>

<p>A simple sauce that is at almost every sushi bar in the United States.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 3 min</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>chili sauce (e.g Sriracha)</li>
<li>mayonnaise</li>
<li>sesame oil</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Add 2 parts mayonnaise to 1 part chili sauce in a bowl.</li>
<li>Add 1 tbsp of sesame oil for every cup of mayonnaise you use.</li>
<li>Mix all of the ingredients together, and taste test it for more chili sauce or mayonnaise.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Note</h2>

<p>This is just a basic guide, adapt this recipe to your liking.</p>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>scary90</li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: basic sauce japanese</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Shakshouka</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/shakshouka.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/shakshouka.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 14:54:36 +0200</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Shakshouka</h1>

<p>Shakshouka is a dish of eggs poached in a sauce of tomatoes, olive oil, peppers, onion and garlic, and commonly spiced with cumin, paprika, cayenne pepper, and nutmeg.
This recipe is a quick and simple version for a delicious breakfast.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 10 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 2</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="pix/shakshouka-02.webp" alt="Shakshouka" /></p>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>5 small tomatoes</li>
<li>5 eggs</li>
<li>1 peeled white onion</li>
<li>some chives</li>
<li>cumin</li>
<li>powdered sweet pepper</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Scald the tomatoes so they are easier to peel.</li>
<li>Peel the tomatoes and cut into cubes</li>
<li>Chop the onion and glaze it on the frying pan with oil</li>
<li>Add tomatoes</li>
<li>SEASON</li>
<li>Stir and wait for it to get denser</li>
<li>Knock the eggs in</li>
<li>Season the eggs
<img src="pix/shakshouka-01.webp" alt="Shakshouka" /></li>
<li>Cover the pan with a lid</li>
<li>Cook until eggs are laid</li>
<li>Add chives</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Jakub Korsak -<a href="https://korsak.xyz">website</a>, <a href="https://korsak.xyz/crypto">donate</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: breakfast quick</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Collard Greens with Smoked Duck and Parsnips</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/collard-greens-with-smoked-duck-and-parnips.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/collard-greens-with-smoked-duck-and-parnips.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 08:49:37 -0400</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Collard Greens with Smoked Duck and Parsnips</h1>

<p>This dish was a pandemic leftover invention loosely inspired by Ethiopian gomen. It can be served as a side dish, but we eat it an an entree. If you intend it as a side dish, then this serves 4. The smoked duck adds a bit of saltiness, so it&rsquo;s better to season to taste after cooking. Serve with good quality, crusty bread.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 20 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 2</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>&frac12; smoked duck breast (skin on) chopped</li>
<li>1 large onion sliced</li>
<li>1 small parsnip julienned</li>
<li>1 large bunch collard greens chopped into ribbons</li>
<li>&frac12; green cabbage cut into ribbons (optional)</li>
<li>1–2 tablespoons olive oil and/or butter</li>
<li>1 teaspoon ground coriander</li>
<li>&frac12; teaspoon cinnamon</li>
<li>&frac12; teaspoon garam masala</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>In a large dutch oven (or a big pot with a lid) on low heat, add the chopped duck breast and olive oil and/or butter to the pot for a couple of minutes. Then add the spices, and cook for a minute or two before adding the sliced onion. Let cook for 5 minutes and then add the parsnip and sweat.</li>
<li>Add the ribboned cabbage and collard greens, a few twists of freshly ground pepper, and two tablespoons of water to the pot and cover. Cook until the greens are wilted and tender to the bite.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Jayson</li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: vegetables sides duck</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hearty Breakfast Oatmeal </title>
<link>https://based.cooking/hearty-breakfast-oatmeal.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/hearty-breakfast-oatmeal.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 07:58:36 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Hearty Breakfast Oatmeal</h1>

<p><img src="pix/hearty-breakfast-oatmeal-00.webp" alt="hearty-breakfast-oatmeal-00" /></p>

<p>If your Oatmeal isn&rsquo;t Hearty Breakfast Oatmeal&hellip; Is it even Oatmeal?</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min</li>
<li>🍳Cook time: 10 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Serving: 1 hearty serving</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>&frac12; cup Large Flake Oats (no partially cooked quick-oats allowed!)</li>
<li>Almonds</li>
<li>Pecans</li>
<li>1 Tbsp Roasted Flax Seed</li>
<li>1 Tbsp Hemp Hearts</li>
<li>Cranberries (adjust amount to preference)</li>
<li>&frac12; Banana (mashed)</li>
<li>1 cup Milk (3.25% if possible)</li>
<li>Cinnamon (adjust amount to preference)</li>
<li>1 Egg</li>
<li>ON Vanilla Ice Cream Protein Powder (optional)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Chop or mash nuts and fruit.</li>
<li>Combine nuts, fruit, and other dry ingredients in a saucepan
<img src="pix/hearty-breakfast-oatmeal-01.webp" alt="hearty-breakfast-oatmeal-01" /></li>
<li>Add milk and cook mixture over medium heat until oats are desired tenderness (5-10 mins)</li>
<li>Add egg and protein powder and cook for a few more minutes</li>
<li>Enjoy</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Joel Farthing - <a href="https://github.com/J-F-Far">GitHub</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: breakfast quick</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Demi-glace</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/demi-glace.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/demi-glace.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 05:52:16 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Demi-glace</h1>

<p>This is a take on a traditional demi-glace without needing to buy an astronomically large amount of veal bones. Use this as your main base for pan sauces, an extra flavor bomb, or a replacement for recipes that call for broth or stock.</p>

<p>These are the basic proportions — multiply as needed. I typically multiply by six to give me several weeks worth of demi-glace ice cubes.</p>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>1 qt (32 oz, 946mL) <strong>low-sodium</strong> broth or stock (I prefer Pacific Foods)</li>
<li>1 &frac14; oz (7g) packet <strong>unflavored, unsweetened</strong> gelatin</li>
<li>1 teaspoon (5mL) tomato paste</li>
<li>1 teaspoon (5mL) <strong>low-sodium</strong> soy sauce</li>
<li>&frac12; teaspoon onion powder (<em>very</em> optional)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Put the tomato paste in a large pot, <em>then</em> turn the heat on medium</li>
<li>Spread the paste around the bottom of the pot and stir until it just barely starts to brown</li>
<li>Deglaze with the broth</li>
<li>Stir in all other ingredients and boil over high heat until reduced to about 1/6th of its original volume</li>
<li>Freeze in ice cub trays</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<p>Dan - ETH <code>0xC86468549c180A296384aAC2F76c8F581691Bc1b</code></p>

<p>;tags: sauce basic french</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Basic Meatballs</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/basic-meatballs.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/basic-meatballs.html</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 04:53:56 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Basic Meatballs</h1>

<p>Hybrid beef/pork meatballs perfect for spaghetti and meatballs or a meatball sub</p>

<ul>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 25 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 4</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>1 pound ground beef (preferably 90/10 or 93/7)</li>
<li>1 pound ground pork</li>
<li>&frac12; cup italian breadcrumbs</li>
<li>1/3 cup milk (I use 2% but doesn&rsquo;t matter too much)</li>
<li>&frac14; cup yellow onion diced (about &frac12; small yellow onion)</li>
<li>1 egg</li>
<li>&frac12; cup shredded parmesan</li>
<li>&frac14;-&frac12; cup chopped parsley</li>
<li>2 tbsp red pepper flakes</li>
<li>2 tbsp dried oregano</li>
<li>1 tbsp rosemary</li>
<li>1 tbsp basil</li>
<li>1 tbsp garlic powder</li>
<li>Salt and pepper to taste</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Preheat oven to 400F</li>
<li>In a bowl, combine all ingredients</li>
<li>Hand form into balls by packing with your hands and then rolling. Set aside on a baking sheet, preferably one with a cooling rack

<ul>
<li>I prefer large meatballs (larger than a golf ball) and shoot for 16-20 for 2 lbs of meat, but if you prefer smaller meatballs you can opt for as many as 48</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Either halfway through the packing process or after forming all meatballs, heat a large skillet to medium-high heat</li>
<li>Add 1-2 tbsp of oil to the skillet (enough to evenly coat the skillet), and bring to heat</li>
<li>Fill the skillet with meatballs, start by browning one face, flip once at after 2-3 minutes, and then remove to the baking sheet after another 2-3 minute. Continue in batches until all meatballs have been browned

<ul>
<li>It is OK and expected for the metaballs to lose some of their spherical shape at this point</li>
<li>You can skip this step and go straight the oven if you want to cut corners</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Transfer to the oven, and cook until the inside registers 140F on an instant read thermometer. This should be about 20 minutes for large meatballs (16 per batch), maybe 10 for small (48 per batch)</li>
<li>Serve with pasta or on a metaball sub</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>John Hubberts <a href="https://github.com/jhubberts">github</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: basic italian beef pork</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ricotta lasagna filling</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/ricotta-lasagna-filling.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/ricotta-lasagna-filling.html</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 02:05:20 +0100</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Ricotta lasagna filling</h1>

<p>A quick and easy filling for lasagna based on ricotta</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 0 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 5-6</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>Ricotta cheese</li>
<li>One large egg</li>
<li>Parmesan cheese</li>
<li>Oregano (Optional)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Mix the ricotta cheese together with a handfull of finely grated parmesan.</li>
<li>Add the oregano and the egg and mix.</li>
<li>Add salt and pepper to taste.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Josiah &ndash; <a href="https://himiko.cloud">website</a>, <a href="https://himiko.cloud/donate/">donate</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: basic italian cheese</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Turkish Yogurt Soup</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/turkish-yogurt-soup.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/turkish-yogurt-soup.html</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 16:55:12 +0300</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Turkish Yogurt Soup</h1>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 35 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 4</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>yogurt</li>
<li>1/3 cup rice</li>
<li>2 tablespoon flour</li>
<li>1 egg yolk</li>
<li>butter</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>wash the rice</li>
<li>put water in the pot and wait for water to boil</li>
<li>add some salt and rice</li>
<li>wait for 15 minutes</li>
<li>mix yogurt, egg and flour and salt in a different bowl</li>
<li>add water from the soup and mix by warming</li>
<li>when the rice is soft, add the yogurt mixture to the soup and mix quickly</li>
<li>cut down the heat, wait for 15 minutes</li>
<li>for the sauce, simply melt the butter in a seperate small pan and stir in the dried mint</li>
<li>add sauteed dried mint to the soup and stir well</li>
<li>serve warm</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>digi - <a href="https://git.sr.ht/~digi/">sourcehut</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: turkish rice soup</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fondue</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/fondue.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/fondue.html</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 14:53:05 +0100</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Fondue</h1>

<p>A swiss classic for cold winter dinners.
Traditionally cooked in a &ldquo;Caquelon&rdquo; pot and served on a candle heated stove, to keep the cheese from going solid again.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 30 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 4</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>1 garlic clove</li>
<li>4 dl (1.5 cups) white wine</li>
<li>800 g (1.7 lbs) swiss cheese (50/50 mix of Gruyère and Emmentaler recommended)</li>
<li>1 shot of kirsch (cherry brandy)</li>
<li>1 tsp lemon juice</li>
<li>1-2 tbsp starch flour</li>
<li>1 loaf (~800g/~1.7 lbs) of white bread</li>
<li>A pinch of nutmeg</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Rub the Pot with garlic clove.</li>
<li>Cut bread into small squares.</li>
<li>Put cheese, starch, wine and lemon juice in pot and melt while stiring constantly.</li>
<li>Season with a bit of pepper and nutmeg.</li>
<li>Serve right away.</li>
<li>Stick bread squares on fondue fork one by one and stir them in the fondue.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>sekthor - <a href="https://github.com/sekthor">github</a>, <a href="mailto:sekthor@protonmail.ch">contact</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: swiss cheese</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spaghetti all'amatriciana</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/spaghetti-all-amatriciana.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/spaghetti-all-amatriciana.html</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 11:46:09 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Spaghetti all'amatriciana</h1>

<p>Ignore the fact that those in the photo are pennette and not spaghetti, that&rsquo;s all I had that day.</p>

<p><img src="pix/spaghetti-all-amatriciana.webp" alt="Jebusthebus" /></p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 25 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 4</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>Pecorino romano cheese preferably or Parmesan 1.5oz (40g)</li>
<li>Fresh chili pepper (as many as you&rsquo;d like)</li>
<li>Extra virgin olive oil &frac14; cup (40g)</li>
<li>Guanciale preferably or Bacon 3.5oz (100g)</li>
<li>White wine &frac14; cup (60g)</li>
<li>Tomato passata 10oz (300g)</li>
<li>Spaghetti or similar long pasta 12oz (350g)</li>
<li>(optional) Extra pecorino romano or parmesan</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Grate the pecorino and keep it aside.</li>
<li>Mince the chili pepper(s) and keep it/them aside.</li>
<li>Cut the guanciale in thin stripes and cook them in the oil with the minced pepper(s) for about 3 minutes on medium/high heat.</li>
<li>Douse with the wine and turn up the heat. Cook until the alcohol has evaporated.</li>
<li>Start <a href="pasta.html">cooking the pasta</a>.</li>
<li>Lower the heat to medium and add the passata, some salt and plenty of pepper. Cook for about 15 minutes.</li>
<li>Once finished, drain the pasta and add the sauce and the pecorino/parmesan, mix well and serve immediately. Optionally you can add some pecorino or parmesan on top.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Jebusthebus</li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: italian pasta</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Garlic Toast</title>
<link>https://based.cooking/garlic-toast.html</link>
<guid>https://based.cooking/garlic-toast.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 23:38:52 +1100</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Garlic Toast</h1>

<p>Garlic toast, perfect as a substitute for crackers in a cheese platter.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>Any kind of firm, thin, sliced bread (Sourdough, Baguette)</li>
<li>Garlic-infused olive oil (Optionally substitute butter or regular olive oil)</li>
<li>Garlic salt</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Preheat oven to 180°C (350°F).</li>
<li>Place sliced bread on a baking tray lined with aluminium foil.</li>
<li>Generously coat bread slices with garlic-infused olive oil.</li>
<li>Season with garlic salt, to taste.</li>
<li>Bake for 10-15 minutes or until crunchy throughout.</li>
<li>Serve with cheese, charcuterie, pickles, dips, or to accommodate a soup.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Jack Crawford - <a href="https://github.com/jjcrawford">website</a></li>
<li>Edited by Zyansheep</li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: basic bread quick side</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
